# ESRA SALIMOVA

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

### PROFILE

Junior web developer with a background in journalism. Experienced in systematic research with a focus on quickly finding the cause of the problem and applying it to the project. Skilled in effective communication and building relationships after years of working in customer service. Persistent in finishing tasks even in challenging conditions.

## CONTACT

+49 (177) 4700508
Elstal, Germany
esrasalimova@gmail.com
https://esrasalimova.github.io/portfolio-website/
linkedin.com/in/esra-salimova-2ab626211
https://github.com/esrasalimova

## SKILLS

JavaScript AWS Node.js

Angular Heroku JQuery

TypeScript MySQL Bootstrap

HTML PostgreSQL React/Native

CSS MongoDB Redux

# LANGUAGES

**Turkish - Native** 

**English - Intermediate** 

**German-Intermediate** 

## EDUCATION

### CareerFoundry · September 2021

#### Full-Stack Immersion

- -Intensive project-based training program with a focus on HTML, CSS, JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks.
- -Designed/Developed a responsive Movie web App by building an external API using Node.js, REST architecture and Mongo DB.

#### **Near East University N.Cyprus • 2014**

MA Communication Sciences

#### **Cyprus International University • 2009**

BA Journalism

# EXPERIENCE

#### **Sales Person. 2017-2020**

Frooters GmbH-Karls Erlebnishof

-Prepared food according to standards and served to ensure best customer experience.

### Call Center Agent, 2015-2017

Convergys GmbH-SELLBYTEL GmbH

- -Assisted customers in choosing the right product that suits their needs.
- -Managed customer complains through resolving their post-order issues, communicated in a way to maintain customer relationship.

### Journalist/Editor, N.Cyprus 2007-2014

Star Media Group

- -Created, researched, investigated data, wrote and published news to assist accurate information for the reader.
- -Assisted in managing newspaper front-end web page.